准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
小心的小蜗
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
小蜗
美食
完美
Perfect
超值装
美食
喂  谁啊
Yes, who is it?
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
嗨  派大星
Hi, Patrick
有什么事
What's going on?
只是在盛装打扮
Just getting dressed
你要出游吗
You wanna hang out?
我现在还不行
I can't right now
今天可是小蜗的重要日子
It's a big day for Gary
小蜗的蜗牛成年礼已经到了吗
His snail-mitzvah already?
不对  那是明天
No, that's tomorrow
今天他得去  看兽医
Today he's going to the V-E-T
虽然想和你去  但我没穿兽衣
I'd join you, but I'm not dressed for the zoo
是看病的那个兽医
The vet, Patrick
小蜗讨厌去兽医院体检
Gary hates going to the vet for his checkup
所以我每次都得骗小蜗进宠物提篮
so I always have to trick him into the pet carrier
我特地留了一道蜗牛粮  放在卫生间
I left a trail of SnailPo treats around the bathroom
引下楼梯
down the stairs
穿过客厅
through the living room
进了厨房
and into the kitchen
小蜗就会在那发现一堆点心  就在
where he'll find a pile of treats right inside
宠物提篮里
his pet carrier
抓到了  小蜗
Gotcha, Gary
你还在吗  派大星
You still there, Patrick?
还在
Still here
派大星
Patrick?
真是好办法  海绵宝宝
Great plan, SpongeBob
小蜗一定会上当的
Gary's gonna fall for it for sure
小蜗
Hey, Gary
让我先
Let me just
这一定比我想的还要难
This is gonna be harder than I thought
再来一点蜗牛粮吧
More snail food, please
蜗牛笑话
好了  小蜗
Okay, Gary
该来单纯散个步了  绝对没另有所图
time for an innocent walk with no ulterior motive
抱歉  小蜗
I'm sorry, Gary
可你得去
but you need to
看医生
see your doctor
真见鬼
Barnacles
可能得来个更诡谲的诡计
Perhaps I'll need a ruse that's even rusier
小蜗  你来了
Gary, you're here
别管那个笨兽医了
Forget that silly veterinarian
我给咱俩预定了豪华热带假期
I booked a big tropical vacation just for the two of us
出游放松一阵子是不是很棒啊
Won't it be nice to just get away for a while and relax?
快进度假提篮里  我们就能起飞了
So just get into that vacation carriage
and we can take off
小蜗  快点进宠物提篮里
Come on, Gary, just get in that pet carrier
嗨  小蜗
Hi, Gary
裤头村机场
小蜗
Gary
放我出去啊
Let me out, boy
乖一点啊
Be a good snail
两周后
好好好  我承认
Okay, okay, I'll admit it
感觉我重返青春了
I feel rejuvenated
你看  小蜗
Look, Gary
这封信是寄给你的
This letter came for you
是封邀请函
It's an invitation
邀请你去败蜗子家开派对
to a big party at Snail Fail's house
他可是这附近最出名的蜗牛
He is the most famous snail in town
邀请函
盛大派对
就在败蜗子家
贵宾
你可是他的贵宾
and you're his VIP
他连豪车都派出来了
He even sent a limousine
你先请  我的大好蜗牛
After you, my good snail
蜗牛粮
是不是很奢华啊
Pretty fancy, huh?
可惜兽医预约看诊只好取消了
A pity we'll have to cancel that vet appointment
我们可绝对不能错过
but there's no way we could miss
派大星
Patrick?
对  我可不容错过
Yeah, I'm pretty hard to miss
小蜗
Gary
命中情蜗
现在回到  命中情蜗
And now back to Snails of Our Lives
要是小蜗不信我说谎
If I can't convince Gary by lying to him
那就非让他信我的逆耳真言不可
I'll have to convince him with brutal honesty
马上实行
Here comes
道德绑架
the guilt trip
下一期  命中情蜗
Next time on Snails of Our Lives
小蜗  我求你了
Gary, I'm begging you
求你去看兽医吧
Please go to the veterinarian
我都担心死你了
I'm worried sick about you
你不会是想让我死吧  小蜗
Do you want me to be sick, Gary?
你该不会还要早早送我入土吧
Are you trying to send me to an early grave?
我愿意为你做任何事  小蜗
I would do anything for you, Gary
任何事
Anything
最佳表演奖得主是
And the winner for best acting is
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
天啊
Oh, my
谢谢
Thank you
能得到提名真是莫大的荣幸
It was an honor just to be nominated
要是你早十一分钟前告诉我
If you had told me eleven minutes ago
海绵宝宝无论如何都会获奖  我
that little old SpongeBob
would win an award for anything, I
等一下
Wait a minute
小蜗
Gary?
见见又鬼鬼
Double barnacles
又让那只滑头蜗牛逃了
That sneaky snail got away again
够了
That's it
我一定要带小蜗看兽医
I am taking Gary to the vet
不择手段
by any means necessary
倘若立下决心
打碎玻璃
再也不当好好海绵先生了
No more Mr. Nice Sponge
猎捕蜗牛时间到
Time for a snail hunt
还是温的
Still warm
刚死的猎物
A fresh kill
小蜗
找到了
Gotcha
看来你正好落入了我的陷阱
I see you've fallen into one of the many traps
我在家里设了不少呢
I've set around the house
能不能给点隐私啊
A little privacy please?
兽医时间
Vet time
这就对了  小蜗
That's it, Gary
跟着红点走
follow the dot
还是理性思考一下吧  小蜗
Let's just think rationally here, Gary
抓到了
Gotcha
兽医
海绵宝宝先生
Mr. SquarePants?
你可以把你家蜗牛带进来了
You may bring in your snail now
天啊  小蜗
Goodness, Gary
你的牙齿可真健康
What healthy teeth you have
小蜗  对好心的医生温柔点
Gary, be nice to the kind doctor
没事的  海绵宝宝先生
That's quite alright, Mr. SquarePants
我知道要怎么对付凶狠的蜗牛
I know exactly how to handle vicious snails
只要用
With a
棒棒糖就行
lollipop
完成了
All done
就这样吗
That's it?
对
Yep
那可是个医用棒棒糖
That's a medical lollipop
里面富含各种维生素和疫苗
full of all the vitamins and vaccinations
全都是蜗牛成长必备的
a growing snail needs
看吧  小蜗
See, Gary?
到头来也不是很糟嘛
That wasn't so bad after all
谢了  医生
Well, thanks, Doctor
明年见
See ya next year
你还不能走  海绵宝宝先生
You can't leave, Mr. SquarePants
你全身都是咬痕和抓痕
You're covered in bites and scratches
对
Yeah
小蜗在来的路上确实有点粗暴了
Gary did get a little rough on the way over here
我应该也有棒棒糖吃吧
I guess I'll take a lollipop, too
不行  海绵可没有棒棒糖吃
Oh, no, sponges don't get lollipops
你可不能遭到感染  所以你得
You don't want to get infected, so you'll need
接受全套治疗
the full treatment
我不想去看兽医啊
I don't wanna go to the vet
千斤压顶
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
五
And five
四
And four
三
And three
二
And two
一
And one
干得漂亮
Great job
你的热身完成了
You've finished your warm-up
再投两毛五  进入真正的健身吧
Now pop in another quarter
and let's get to the real workout
今天热个身就行  鹈鹕机器先生
Just the warm-up today, Mr. Pelican machine
接下来的健身活动是
And now for my next workout
打拳击吊袋
The speed bag
好
Yes
我爱痛苦
感受身体燃烧
Feel the burn
燃烧
Burning
好耶
Oh, yeah
今天  我要推向极限
Today, I am pushing it to the limit
该来破自己记录了
Time for a new personal best
过
Half
半
way
了
there
我被压住了
I'm pinned
海绵宝宝  你能想出解决办法的
Okay, SpongeBob, you can figure this out
冷静下来
Just keep calm
什么都看不见
Can't see anything
有了
I know
用脚指头走路就行
I'll let my foot fingers do the walking
这里肯定有东西能帮得上忙
There's gotta be something in here that can help me
不行  太多齿了
Nope, too toothy
太辣了
Too spicy
太撬棍了
Too crowbar-y
太躁动了
Too snappy
不行
No good
我要怎么
What am I gonna
小蜗可以救我
Gary will save me
小蜗
Gary
进来  兄弟
Come in here, buddy
喵喵喵喵
我需要你
I need you
求你了  小蜗
Please, Gary?
小蜗
Garebear
一小时后
拜托  小蜗
Come on, Gary
我需要你
I need you
小蜗
Gary
谢天谢地
Thank goodness
我被压在这杠铃底下了
I'm trapped beneath this bar
拜托帮我弄下来
Come get it off me, please
快
Hurry
对
Yeah
你这样就对了  小蜗
You're doing it, Gary
再靠近一点
Just a little closer
你在干嘛  兄弟
What are you doing, buddy?
可怜的小家伙都累坏了
Poor little guy's all tuckered out
不过不太确定这有没有帮上忙
Not sure this is helping me though
等下
Wait
小蜗向来都会往自己壳里放签字笔
Gary always keeps a journaling pen inside his shell
找到了
Eureka
求救
"Send help
我被困在楼上健身房的杠铃下了
I've become trapped under my weights in my upstairs gym
我名字叫海绵宝宝
My name is SpongeBob
我家蜗牛的名字叫小蜗
My snail's name is Gary
小蜗也在  不过睡着了
Gary is here too, but he fell asleep
所以我只能靠你了  好心的陌生人
so I'm relying on you, kind stranger"
我得救马上就只是时间问题了
Soon it'll be just a matter of time before I'm rescued
海草哥
真是的
Come on
怎么回事
What's the big idea?
这玩意谁扔的
Alright, who threw this?
给我得了  大聪明
That does it, wisenheimer
裤头村警察局
Bikini Bottom Police Department
需要什么公安服务
How may I protect and serve?
有人袭击
An assault
裤头村绝不能出这种事
Not in our town
我们马上派出警船
We'll send a squad boat right away
前往警船
To the cop mobile
开船
Hit it
听到了吧  神秘恶棍
You hear that, mysterious miscreant?
你马上就要
You are so
有救了
Saved
小蜗  我有救了
Gary, I'm saved
话说地址在哪来着
What was that address again?
停
是
It's
章鱼哥
Squidward
天啊  那家伙老是乱报警
Man, that guy's always calling
对啊  上次他报警是因为
Yeah, last time it was because of
自家客厅闯进了一只海苍蝇
a trespassing sea-fly in his living room
该死  他在那
Oh, shrimp, there he is
弯下去
Duck
在这  警官
Over here, officers
什么
What
怎么
What the?
起码警察那边确实有说要派出警船
Well, they did say they were gonna send a squad boat
白痴一群
Idiots
警察没停船
They didn't stop
一定要把瓶子撞出窗外
Must knock bottle out of window
这些健身器材终于能派上用场了
Finally I can put these gym tools to use
没东西可扔了
Nothing left to throw
除了
Except
小蜗
Gary
抱歉  兄弟
Sorry, buddy
你是我唯一的希望了
you're my only hope
好了  小蜗
Okay, Gary
来把瓶子砸出窗外
try to knock the bottle out of the window
这下彻底玩完了
I've really done it now
所有希望都破灭了
All hope is lost
能试的都试了  结果全失败了
I've tried everything and failed
所有想得到的逃生机会  都用尽了
All conceivable chances of escape, exhausted
对了  有电话
Oh yeah, the phone
海神王啊  救命
Sweet Neptune, help me
我在我家健身房被杠铃压住了
I'm pinned under weights in my home gym
回答正确
That's correct
直播
今日金曲就是
The song of the day is
海神王啊  救命
"Sweet Neptune, Help Me
我在我家健身房被杠铃压住了
I'm Pinned Under Weights in My Home Gym"
海神王啊  救命
我在我家健身房
被杠铃压住了
无赖老水手乐队
由无赖老水手乐队演唱
by Scalawag and the Sea Dogs
这位听众  你赢得了一千元
Listener, you just won $1,000
我我
I-I
有吗
I did?
对
Yeah
接下来十分钟内抵达电台即可领取
If you can get down here to the station
in the next 10 minutes
深K电台  专播金曲
K-DEEP, we play the hits
别
No
别挂啊
Don't hang up
太扯了
Oh, fiddlesticks
要是我用脚趾随便拨几个号
If I randomly hit numbers with my toe
肯定可以叫到几个谁
I'm sure to call somebody
喂
Hello?
拉里
Larry
我需要你的帮助
I need your help
我被困在我杠铃底下了
I'm trapped under my weights
虽然很希望能帮到你  兄弟
I wish I could help you, bro
但是
but
拉里自己都有问题
Larry's got problems of his own
喂
Hello?
喂  什么事啊
Yes, what is it?
你说被困住了吗
Trapped, you say?
就自己一个
All alone?
而且还动弹不得吗
And you can't move?
听起来
That sounds
真难受
excruciating
抱歉  打错了
Sorry, wrong number
这可不好
That's not good
很多小时后
救  救命
H-help
救命
help
现在谁都不会来救你了  海绵宝宝
There's no one who can help you now, SpongeBob
谁都不会
No one
不对
No
我朋友会找到我的
my friends will find me
怎么找
How?
他们连你在哪都不知道
They don't even know where you are
但我们知道你在哪  大笨蛋
But we know where you are, big silly
我们直到你生命尽头都会是你朋友
We'll be your friends to the end of your days
有客人来
A visitor?
我有救了
I'm saved
进来
Come in
在吗
Hello?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
你在家吗
Are you home?
在这上面
Up here
我在
I'm up
这上面
here
什么都没听到
I don't hear anything
没有危险
The coast is clear
天啊
Oh, boy
这一定会是海绵宝宝这辈子
This is gonna be the best surprise party
最厉害的惊喜派对
SpongeBob's ever had
听见没  小蜗
You hear that, Gary?
我马上就自由了
Soon I'll be free
万岁
Hooray
救
H
救命
Help
我在
I'm
楼上
upstairs
不知道楼上有什么好玩的
I wonder what kind of fun stuff is up there?
有救了
Saved
你们干什么  小子
What are ye doing, lads?
只准在楼下指定的派对区嬉笑打闹
Keep your mirth and mayhem downstairs
in the designated party area
遵命  船长
Aye, aye, Captain
别走
Wait
回来
Come back
没用的
It's no use
他们听不见我的求救声
They can't hear my voice
但可能可以听得见我的脚步声
But maybe they can hear my foot's voice
安静
Quiet
你们听见没
Do you hear that?
我认得这首船歌
I know this shanty
海神王啊  救命
Sweet Neptune, help me
我在我家健身房被杠铃压住了
I'm pinned under weights in my home gym
我的老天  我本想锻炼
By Jove, by Jim I tried to be trim
却在我家健身房被杠铃压住了
I'm pinned under weights in my home gym
我试图变壮  但远远不够
I tried to get buff but it wasn't enough
重压之下  举步维艰
When the weight had its way, the going got tough
不能摇不能垫
No shimmy or shim
我的颤抖四肢
My quivering limbs
在我家健身房被杠铃压住了
Pinned under weights in my home gym
快将杠铃举过身
So, hoist the barbells over lads
尚未入水就会沉
They'll sink before they swim
早知道就多花点钱
I knew I should have paid extra
修个防船歌地板了
for the shanty-proof floor
惊喜
Surprise
蟹堡王
所以我今早才差点上班迟到
And that's why I was almost late for work this morning
别浪费时间了  快干活
Stop your lollygagging and get to work
遵命  蟹老板
Aye, aye, Mr. Krabs, sir
上菜了
Order up